Preliminary Inventory to the Clarence Reed Papers WAG.015
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Clarence Reed Papers
1957-1974
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Reed, Clarence, 1909-
WAG.015
0.25 Linear Feet (1 box)
Historical/Biographical Note
Clarence Reed was born in New York City in 1909. After working at odd jobs in the army, in lumber camps, and on the railroad, he became active in the Unemployed Councils and the Friends of the Soviet Union in the 1930s. He found work with a shipping company during World War II, when he joined the National Maritime Union. After the War, Reed was expelled from the Communist Party and helped establish a rank and file committee in the NMU. The rank and file committee ran slates of candidates against the incumbent union leadership and concentrated on the problems of corruption and drugs within the NMU's ranks.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Clarence Reed at an unknown date. The accession number associated with this gift is 1974.007.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists mainly of correspondence and other material regarding Reed's activity in the National Maritime Union and his 1973-74 campaign for union office. Also included are union constitutions, copies of cartoons by Reed on union issues, and miscellaneous correspondence. The archives also has an oral history interview and a play written by Reed in 1984.
Political cartoons.; Constitutions.; Press releases.; Labor union democracy.; Correspondence.; Labor unions |x Corrupt practices.; Labor unions -- Elections.; Labor leaders -- United States.; Lumber trade |x Employees.; Communists -- United States.; Collective bargaining -- United States.; Merchant mariners |x Labor unions |z United States.; National Maritime Union of America; Reed, Clarence, 1909-
- Inventory
  - Correspondence with National Maritime Union, Jun 1, 1971-Jun 29, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Notes Regarding Court Case Involving Harassment of President Curran's Son, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Election Material, Press Release, and Notes for Clarence Reed's Campaign, [1973?] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General, 1967-1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Government Labor Publications, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Maritime Union Constitutions, 1957, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons by Reed on Union Issues (originals), circa 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons by Reed on Union Issues (copies), circa 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Legal Materials and Notes Regarding Challenge to Election, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)